

{Ikhsan Maulana}

Banda Aceh, Aceh, | +681214710491 | ikhsanmou95@gmail.com

Personal Profile

I am Ikhsan Maulana, and I grew up in Aceh on October 20, 1995. I graduated from the State Islamic University Ar Raniry Banda Aceh in 2018 with a degree in Arabic Language and Literature. I am also interested in IT technology and the translation of Arab manuscripts, and I attended cloud computing training at ITB Bandung at the end of 2018, which was sponsored by Kominfo and Microsoft Indonesia, as well as an introduction to full stack developer training held by the digital talent scholars, I've worked as an administrative assistant, a web developer, and a manuscript translator at Aly Hasjmy Library, as well as a manuscript translation author at Do Karim Banda Aceh Agency. I am interested in a career in IT technology, either as a front-end developer or a back-end developer, and I am also very interested in the translation of Arabic manuscripts and text editing, as well as being active in speaking Arabic or English and skilled in using Microsoft Office Tools.

Skills and Abilities Summary

- Microsoft Office Tools
- Data Management
- Arabic Language (Advanced)
- English (Intermediate)

- HTML & CSS
- JavaScript
- Node.Js
- Python
- MySQL

Work Experience

The Library of Aly Hasjmy

Staff Administrasi (july 2017 – june 2018)

- Responsible for checking the administration of visitors every day from the address, destination, to the process of borrowing the script.
- Improve the effectiveness of handling the script to protect it from harm caused by biological variables, physical factors, the script's age, and other things.

Do Karim Writing Institute

As a Translator and Writer (August 2018 – November 2019)

• Translating the book Tajul Muluk discusses Nujum (Astronomy) which was later titled the Book of Marabahaya and edited by Fauzan Santa (Rektor Do Karim).

Mini Project Python

Developed an ATM Application

• Specify the application flow. Specify features such as: check pin, change pin, check balance, debit or withdraw, save or deposit, exit, and print a transaction summary.

Mini Project Login Screen

• Using Google OAuth, by modifying instagram to not instagram using index.html, style.css, and script.js.

Mini Project Jan-Ken Game

Event Listener, math random, and local storage

• Create Jan-ken Games, also known as Suit-Japanese, with page layout: reset buttons, Ninja Ken, scoreboard, stone button, cut button, paper button, and make JavaScript the game's brain. This game is played through a web browser.

Educational History

Ar - Raniry Islamic University (2013 – 2018)

Bachelor of Arabic Language and Literature - Grade 3.21

- Become a sports representative of the HMJ Faculty of Adab and Humniora.
- Member of the Writing of Do Karim Institute
- Representative of HMJ for Al Washliyah Banda Aceh leadership training.
- Followed the training of the Digitalent Scholarship Program in 2018 at the Institute of Technology Bandung (ITB) with the Cloud Server Administration program sponsored by Microsoft Indonesia.
- Followed the Intro to Full Stack Developer Training Program in 2021, sponsored by Progate Indonesia.
- Followed the student scholarship program Tahfiz Al Quran in 2019 at Darul Qur'an Tangerang sponsored by the Ayatt Charity Association

Rewarded

KOMINFO & Microsoft Indonesia (15 Oktober s.d 06 Desember 2018)

• ITB (Institute Of Technology Bandung) Digitalent Scholarship 2018 in Cloud Computing

Ayatt Charity Association & Darul Qur'an Tangerang (01 Maret s.d 07 Maret 2019)

Teacher scholarship for the Tahfidzh Qur'an program at Darul Ulum Tanggerang

Digital talent scholarship & progate Indonesia (12 Agustus s.d 25 Agustus 2021)

• Introduction to the full stack developer scholarship program, sponsored by Kominfo and Progate Indonesia.